<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>social-science on Stephanie Kirmer</title>
    <link>https://skirmer.github.io/tags/social-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social-science on Stephanie Kirmer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://skirmer.github.io/tags/social-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning’s Public Perception Problem</title>
      <link>https://skirmer.github.io/writing/machinelearningspublicperceptionproblem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skirmer.github.io/writing/machinelearningspublicperceptionproblem/</guid>
      <description>Why machine learning literacy for the public needs to be a priority for data science, and what we can do about it.
I was listening to a podcast recently with an assortment of intelligent, thoughtful laypeople (whose names I will not share, to be polite) talking about how AI can be used in healthcare. I had misgivings already, because they were using the term “AI”, which I find frequently means everything and nothing at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Sociologically About Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://skirmer.github.io/writing/thinkingsociologicallyaboutmachinelearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skirmer.github.io/writing/thinkingsociologicallyaboutmachinelearning/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes mention in my written work and speeches that I have a sociology background, and used to be an adjunct professor of sociology at DePaul University before embarking on my data science career. I loved sociology, and still do — it shaped so much about how I understand the world and my own place in it.
However, when I made a career change and turned to data science, I spent a lot of time explaining how that background, training, and experience were assets to my practice of data science, because it wasn’t obvious to people.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
