<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>office-hours on Stephanie Kirmer</title>
    <link>https://skirmer.github.io/tags/office-hours/</link>
    <description>Recent content in office-hours on Stephanie Kirmer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://skirmer.github.io/tags/office-hours/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating New Data Scientists in the Age of Remote Work</title>
      <link>https://skirmer.github.io/writing/creatingnewdatascientistsintheageofremotework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skirmer.github.io/writing/creatingnewdatascientistsintheageofremotework/</guid>
      <description>Learning how to be a professional data scientist is different now, but it’s not impossible
Today’s column is partly about data science, but it’s also about the sociology of work. As a senior practitioner in the field, I started my data science career long before Covid-19 and the radical shift in the way we work today developed. I started my professional career years before even that. As a result, my years of learning how to be a professional anything, let alone a professional data scientist, were spent in close quarters with much more experienced people, and in many ways that made it possible for me to get where I am.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Engineers — what do they actually do?</title>
      <link>https://skirmer.github.io/writing/machinelearningengineers-whatdotheyactuallydo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://skirmer.github.io/writing/machinelearningengineers-whatdotheyactuallydo/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning Engineers — What Do They Actually Do? Does “Machine Learning Engineer” mean something new to our field? If so, what?
The title is a trick question, of course. Much like Data Scientist before it, the title Machine Learning Engineer is developing into a trend in the job market for people in our profession, but there is no consensus about the meaning of the title or the functions and skills it should encompass.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
